ARNOLD BRECHT PAPERS (GER024) 1865-1974
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Arnold Brecht Papers1865-1974
nam_ger024
Brecht, Arnold, 1884-1977
14.67
Correspondence in German and English with Otto Braun, Heinrich Bruning, Jürgen Fehling, Theodore Heuss, and others, 1933–1970; lectures, notes, and syllabi, 1934–1938; offprints; and manuscripts of published and unpublished works, 1950–1970. Brecht was a Prussian official who was dismissed after defying Hitler in the last free speech in the German parliament. He was a professor of political science, public finance, and international law at the New School for Social Research. His principal work was Political Theory (Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press, 1959). This manuscript group was photocopied by the University Libraries with Brecht's permission before the originals were sent to the Bundesarchiv, Koblenz, Germany.
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Biographical Sketch
Arnold Brecht was born in 1884 in Lübeck, Germany. After completing his university studies in Bonn, Berlin, Göttingen and Leipzig, he received his Doctor of Law degree from Leipzig in 1906. In 1910, Brecht's career turned to civil service. From 1910 to 1933, he served under seven Reich Chancellors and more than a dozen Reich and Prussian ministers, until he was formally dismissed from his position as acting state secretary by Hitler in 1933.
Upon the invitation of Alvin Johnson, Brecht emigrated to the U.S. in 1933 to become one of the initial members of the newly formed "University in Exile", the Graduate Faculty of Political and Social Science of the New School for Social Research in New York City. Brecht remained on the Faculty of the New School until his retirement in 1954, after which he continued to lecture as an Emeritus Professor of Political Science and Jurisprudence until 1963.
In addition to his teaching and lecturing, Brecht was also called upon to advise the United States Military (OMGUS - Office of Military Government for Germany) in the rebuilding of Germany after World War II, as well as serving as an Expert to the Secretary of the Army, and a lecturer in the Army Specialized Training Programs at City College, Harvard and Haverford Colleges.
Arnold Brecht's publications, dating from his law school years, encompass the areas of civil law, international relations, political science and theory, and political, constitutional and administrative problems of his day. His best-known work, Political Theory. The Foundations of Twentieth Century Political Thought, has been reprinted several times as well as translated into German, Portuguese and Spanish. Brecht's rich and influential life and career are detailed in his memoirs, published first in German in two volumes (Aus nächster Nähe and Mit der Kraft des Geistes) in 1966 and 1967 respectively, and later condensed and released in an English edition under the title The Political Education of Arnold Brecht in 1970. Brecht died while on a visit to Germany on September 11, 1977.
Chronology of Events:
1884 January 26, born in Lübeck, Germany; father Ernst Walther Brecht, mother Marie (Weishaupt) Brecht.
1902 Completed his Abitur from the Gymnasium, Lübeck
1902-1905 Attended universities in Bonn, Berlin, Göttingen and Leipzig.
1905 Studied in France.
1905-1909 In-service training in Hannover province and Berlin.
1906 Awarded Dr. juris utriusque from the University of Leipzig.
1910 Completed state examinations. Judge in Lübeck.
1910-1917 Counsellor to the Reich Ministries of Justice.
1911-1913 Secretary of the Governmental Commission for the Reform of the Penal Code.
1914-1917 Judge in Berlin.
1918 Counsellor to the Reich Ministry of Economics.
1918-1921 Counsellor to the Reich Chancellry; also Secretary of the Reich Cabinet
1919 Appointed Privy Counsellor.
1921-1927 Ministerial Director of the Reich Ministry of the Interior.
1927 Research on Public Administration in France and England.
1927-1933 Ministerial Director of the Prussian State Ministry and Finance Ministry. Representative of Prussia in German Reichsrat and rapporteur for federal budget. Vice-President of Reich Debt Commission. Member of the supervisory councils of the Reich Post Office and Federal Public Works. Lecturer in public law at the Hochschule für Politik. Vice-president, Institute for Economy, Public Administration.
1928-1930 Member, Reich Reform Commission.
1932 Leading representative and counsel for the Prussian government in procedure at Leipzig Supreme Court after the Papen coup.
1933 Emigrated to the U.S. to join the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research, NY.
1933-1963 Professor of Political Science, Jurisprudence and Public Finance, Graduate Faculty, New School for Social Research.
1937, 1940 Visiting lecturer on government at Harvard University, Spring terms.
1942-1945 Chairman of the Special Committee on Comparative Government, Public Administration Committee, Social Science Research Council.
1943-1944 Lecturer, Civil Affairs Training Schools, Harvard and Yale. Supervisor of the Army Specialized Training Program, German area, City College, NY; also lecturer at ASTP, Harvard, Bard, Haverford.
1944 Woodward lecturer, Yale University, Spring term.
1945-1950 Member, Research Council, Institute of World Affairs, New School for Social Research.
1946 Became U.S. citizen. Third Vice President, American Political Science Association and member of its Research Committee (1946- ).
1948 May -- Sept., Expert to Secretary of the Army and consultant to OMGUS.
1952, 1954 Guest professor at University of Heidelberg, Summer semester.
1953 Appointed ex post to Staatssekretär by the Bonn Government.
1954 Became Emeritus Professor at the New School, March 15.
1959 First publication of Political Theory. The Foundations of Twentieth Century Political Thought. Awarded Das Grosse Verdienstkreuz der Bundesrepublik Deutschland.
1960 Received the Woodrow Wilson Foundation Award for the best political science work of 1959 (Political Theory).
1964 Awarded honorary Doctor of Letters degree from the New School for Social Research, upon the occasion of his 80th birthday.
1970 Jan. 26, awarded Das Grosse Verdienstkreuz mit Stern. June 24, death of Clara Brecht.
1973 Sept. 25, presented the New School Graduate Faculty Founders Medal.
1974 Jan. 26, celebrated his 90th birthday.
1977 Sept. 11, died in Eutin/Schleswig-Holstein, while on a visit to Germany.
Scope and Content Information
The Arnold Brecht Papers, 1865-1974, consist of 14.67 cu. ft. of materials and are primarily copies of original documents, letters and printed materials housed at the Bundesarchiv, Koblenz, Germany ( Bundesarchiv, Potsdamer Strasse 1, 56075 Koblenz, Germany or http://www.bundesarchiv.de/ ).
The collection is divided into six series: 1) Biographical and autobiographical materials, family documents, 1865-1974; 2) Correspondence, 1905-1976; 3) Writings of Arnold Brecht, 1904-1976; 4) Course and lecture notes, notes and clippings on various lecture topics, 1935-1963; 5) Writings by others, 1939-1974; and 6) Collections of materials (primarily clippings) on topics of interest. The writings of Brecht (Series 3) have been further divided into two Sub-series: 1) Full-length (book) publications, 1906-1974; and 2) Essayistic and literary writings, 1904-1976.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Biographical and Autobiographical Materials, Family Documents, 1865-1974
Series 2: Correspondence, 1905-1976
Series 3: Writings of Arnold Brecht, 1904-1976
Subseries 1: Full-length (Book) Publications, 1906-1974
Subseries 2: Essayistic and Literary Writings, 1904-1976
Series 4: Course and Lecture Notes, Notes and Xlippings on Various Lecture Topics, 1935-1963
Series 5: Writings by Others, 1939-1974
Series 6: Collections of Materials on Various Topics of Interest
.
Series arrangement statement: SUNY will complete.
Acquisition Information
The originals of the Brecht Papers are located in the Bundesarchiv, Koblenz, Germany (Bundesarchiv, Potsdamer Strasse 1, 56075 Koblenz, Germany or http://www.bundesarchiv.de/). This manuscript group was photocopied by the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, with Brecht's permission before the originals were sent to the Bundesarchiv.
Access
Collection is open to use, without restrictions.
Subject and Genre Headings
Public Servants; Political Science; Military and Armed Conflict; Brecht, Arnold, 1884-1977.; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.: 1919-1997); Political science -- Study and teaching.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees.; Law -- Study and teaching.
Container List
- Biographical and Autobiographical Materials, Family Documents, 1865-1974; 1; 98 file folders
  The materials in this series document Brecht's life and career, both in Germany before 1933, as well as after his arrival in the United States. This series contains a number of documents relating to Brecht's career as Counsellor in the Reich Ministries of Justice (1910-1917) and Economics (1918), and the Reich Chancellry (1918-1921), as well as Ministerial Director in the Reich Ministry of the Interior (1921-1927) and various other ministries including the Prussian State Ministry and Finance Ministry (1927-1933), until his final dismissal by Hitler in 1933. Also included in this series are materials related to Brecht's activities as Expert to the Secretary of the Army (1948), as well as materials pertaining to HICOG (High Commissioner for Germany).
  Arranged chronologically
  - Weishaupt, Theodor (grandfather). Documents, 1865-1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Birth and baptismal certificates (Arnold Brecht, Clara Berg), 1877; 1884 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - School documents, 1896-1901 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student newspapers, 1898-1899 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary, entitled "In schöner Zeit", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Silver wedding anniversary celebration of Brecht's parents, 1902 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Materials pertaining to Brecht's legal studies, 1903-1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal letters and employment records, 1905-1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Employment records, Reichsjustizministerium (Reich Ministry of Justice), 1905-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Teaching evaluations, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "System der Vertragshaftung", 1908 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Reviews & correspondence.
  - Reich Ministry of Justice, 1910-1918 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Notes, correspondence.
  - Reports and correspondence concerning Belgium, 1910-1918 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Marriage certificate, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Military documents, 1915-1917 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Propaganda campaign, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - World War I, treaties & correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brecht's appointment to "Kaiserliche Regierungsrat", 1918 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brecht's notes on Cabinet meetings, 1918 October 29-1918 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brecht's notes on Cabinet meeting, 1918 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Reports on the November Revolution, 1918 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Press conferences of the Reich Chancellry, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Vorgeschichte des Waffenstillstandes. Amtliche Urkunden, herausgegeben im Auftrage des Reichsministeriums von der Reichskanzlei. Printed copy, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Documents relating to Brecht's position at the Reich Chancellry, 1918-1921 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Materials relating to the Kapp-Putsch, 1920 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence relating to Brecht's leaving the Reich Chancellry, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Aufzeichnung über meine Unterredung mit Polizeipräsident Pohner auf seinem Amtszimmer am Donnerstag, den 10. Februar 1921 in München..." Transcript prepared by Brecht, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brecht's account of his work for the Reich Ministry of the Interior, 1921-1927 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Celebration in the Paulskirche, Frankfurt, 1923 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Last Will and Testament of Marie Brecht, 1925 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Record of trips to London and Paris, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Documents and correspondence pertaining to Brecht's dismissal from the Reichsministerium des Innern, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Official documents pertaining to service in the Staatsministerium and Reichsrat, 1927-1933 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Articles pertaining to Reichsreform, 1926-1931 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Brecht's speeches on Reichsreform, 1926-1931 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Die Beschlüsse des Verfassungsausschusses der Länderkonferenz". Reports by Brecht, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper clippings on Reichsreform, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Verfassungsausschuß der Länderkonferenz" (record of the meeting of the Constitutional Committee of the Conference of States), 1930 June 20-1930 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Gesetz über die Reichsreform". Brecht's comments, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence and clippings pertaining to Reichsreform, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence concerning Brecht's first visit to U.S., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence concerning trip to California, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Programs of lectures, panel discussions, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Brecht's correspondence (Erwin Widder, Ernst Günther Prüfs, Gerhard Schulz, Jürgen Bay) concerning Reichsreform, 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Blätter des Deutschlandbundes. Copies of publication, notes, 1931 February 6-1932 August 24 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brecht's recommendations on unemployment situation in Germany, 1932 March (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Materials concerning von Papen's coup d'état, 1932 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Including statement by Brecht.
  - Documents concerning Brecht's first dismissal by von Papen, 1932 July (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Prussia vs. Deutsches Reich trial. Documents and clippings, 1932 July 20 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Prussia vs. Deutsches Reich. Documents and proceedings, 1933 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Documents concerning Brecht's second dismissal, 1933 February (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Report of Brecht's final days at the Staatsministerium, 1933 March (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Brecht's report of his arrest, 1933 April 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Documents and correspondence concerning Brecht's third dismissal, 1933 August (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Printed materials and notes on the Hitler regime, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Appointment to the Faculty of the New School for Social Research & departure from Germany, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Departure from Germany, 1933 November 9 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Arriving in America". Printed version of Brecht's retrospective essay (1970), and notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Our Life Story". Documents and correspondence, documenting Brecht's activities, ca. 1933-1954 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Transcripts of important letters received by Brecht, 1934; 1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Social Science Research Council, Committee on Comparative Administration, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Army Specialized Training Courses, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    City College, 1942-1944; Harvard, 1944.
  - Brecht's work for Council for Democracy, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Reports on activities, 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Brecht's appointment by the City of Hamburg to the Executive Committee of the Bizonal Economic Council, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and reports on Brecht's work in Germany as "Expert to the Secretary of the Army", 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Meine Mission in Deutschland 1948 als 'Expert to the Secretary of the Army'". Brecht's notes and reports, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Brecht's suggestions to the new German Constitution, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - HICOG (High Commissioner for Germany). Correspondence, notes, reports, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notes on trip to Washington, 1951 January (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Mission to Heidelberg, 1952 Summer (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Report and related correspondence, trip to Germany, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence concerning University of Heidelberg, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Hula, Erich. "Arnold Brecht's Contribution to Comparative Government and International Relations". Article written on the occasion of Brecht's 70th birthday, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Friedrich, C.J. "Arnold Brecht. Jurist and Political Theorist", 1954 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Fulbright Award, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence relating to trip to Bonn, Germany, 1955 June (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Award of Das Grosse Verdienstkreuz des Verdienstordens der Bundesrepublik Deutschland, 1959 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation Award, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Poems dedicated to Brecht by Ernest Hocking, Herbert Bailey, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 80th birthday honors, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Honorary degree, New School for Social Research, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Award of Das Grosse Verdienstkreuz mit Stern, 1970 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Death certificate of Clara Brecht, 1970 June 24 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Presentation of Graduate Faculty Founders Medal, 1973 September 25 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 90th birthday honors, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 90th birthday, press clippings, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "Erinnerungen und Geschichte. Ein autobiographischer Versuch", Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Notes to volume 1 of Brecht's autobiography.
  - "Ungedruckte Teile meines Lebenserinnerungen", Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Various versions, including deleted sections of Brecht's autobiography.
  - "Aus nächster Nähe". Appendices, materials to autobiography, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Notes, title suggestions to English version of autobiography, Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Biographical notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Curriculum vitae, various versions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Lexicon entries, Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Lists of publications, Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Index cards of Brecht's publications, Undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Listing of Brecht's papers given to the Bundesarchiv, Koblenz, Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Articles, clippings about Brecht, Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Correspondence, 1905-1976; 2; 319 file folders
  The correspondence files span a period of over 70 years, with the bulk of the correspondence dating from the years 1933-1976. The correspondence has been arranged alphabetically within several categories: family, professional and general, students, politicians and public officials (U.S. and Germany), administrative and faculty members of the New School for Social Research, and organizational correspondence. The professional and general correspondence includes substantial amounts between Brecht and Julie Braun-Vogelstein, Jürgen Fehling, Carl Joachim (Achim) Friedrich, Kurt von Fritz, Ernest Hamburger, Ernest Hocking, Fritz Morstein-Marx and Gustav and Lydia Radbruch, as well as with former students Morris Forkosch and Alfred J. Jung. The collection also contains correspondence with the American statesman John Foster Dulles, as well as lengthy exchanges with German statesmen Otto Braun, Heinrich Brüning, Ferdinand Friedensburg and Theodor Heuss. The series also contains Brecht's correspondence with other members of the New School for Social Research, most notably with former New School Deans Alvin Johnson, Hans Simons and Hans Staudinger.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Family members, 2.1
    - Barthels, Dorothea (niece), 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brecht, Marie (née Weishaupt, mother), 1909 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Brecht, Gustav (brother), 1909; 1945-1948; 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Brecht, Gustav. Copies of affidavits, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Brecht, Rolf (brother), 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Schnirlin, Gertrud (née Brecht), sister, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General correspondence, 2.2
    - A -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Adolph, Hans J. L., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Albert, Heinrich F. & Ida, 1933-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Alexander, Edgar, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Almond, Gabriel A., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Anderson, William, 1940-1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Andrea, Erich & Fritz, 1948; 1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Angell, Ernest (Council for Democracy), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Anspach, Ernst, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Archiv für Rechts- und Sozialphilosophie, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Arendt, Hannah, 1960; 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Arnold, Fritz W., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Ascher, Charles S., 1941-1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Aussenpolitik, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - B -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Baerensprung, H.W., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Baerwald, Friedrich (Thought), 1942 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Balasundaram, Palayam M., 1951-1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Banse, Herman, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Barth, Eberhard, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Barth, Max, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Bauer, Friedrich, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bausch, Hans A., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bay, Jürgen, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Bayerische Rundfunk, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Beard, Charles A., 1942-1948 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Beck, Earl R., 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Behn, Fritz, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Behn, Irmgard, 1952-1971 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Behn, Richard, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Benda, Emanuel, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Benda, Gabi, 1948; 1954 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Benda, Christian, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Bergsträsser, Arnold, 1946; 1954 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Berman, David, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Bernsdorf, Wilhelm (Wörterbuch der Soziologie), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Berolzheimer, Josef, 1934-1955 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Bilfinger, Käthe, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Blencke, Erna, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Borsig, Tet Arnold von, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Bracher, Karl, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Brammer, Karl, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Brand, Hanna, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, 1946-1971 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Brenner-Rademacher, Susanna, 1964; 1968 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Breunig, Else, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Brockhaus, Paul, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Brodersen, Arvid, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Brodie, William, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Brook, Warner F., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Bülow, Andreas von, 1958; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Bundesarchiv Koblenz, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Burdine, J. Alton, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1934; 1936; 1939 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Byrnes, Eugene H., 1939 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - C -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Cahn, Edmund, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Caldwell, Lynton K., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - California Law Review, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Catlin, George E. Gordon, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Chaudhry, Iqbal Nath, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Claussen, Dean O., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Coker, Francis W., 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Cole, Taylor, 1946-1950; 1959 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Colegrove, Kenneth, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Cook, Thomas I., 1953; 1961 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Corwin, Edward S., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Crome, Otto, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - D -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Daetz, Maria Mercedes, 1950-1974 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Daetz, Lily, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 54)